toolingu.com 2015-05-28

# Privacy Statement | Tooling U-SME

Tooling University LLC (the "Company" or "Tooling University") is committed to protecting your online privacy while you use the services provided by the Company. We urge you to read this privacy statement in its entirety so that you will understand all of the practices and procedures that relate to your online privacy. Tooling University provides high-quality, web-based training on a wide variety of industrial manufacturing topics. This Privacy Statement applies generally to visitors of the Tooling University website (the "Website") and users of its services, including schools and employers. Students enrolled in Tooling University courses ("Students") are also subject to Student Privacy Statement.

  * ### Overview

This Privacy Statement addresses your privacy by:

    * **Informing you about:**
      * the type of personal information the Company collects about you through this Website;
      * how that information is collected;
      * the general purposes for which information is collected;
      * what disclosures of information will be made;
      * how, and to what extent, you can limit those disclosures; and

    * **Assuring you that:**
      * reasonable precautions are taken to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosures, alteration, or destruction;
      * Company employees who have access to your personal information are informed about our privacy procedures for protecting such information;
      * reasonable policies and procedures are in place to insure that the Company gathers only the information it needs in order to perform the tasks listed below and that your personal information is retained only as long as necessary for the purposes for which it was gathered;
      * reasonable policies and procedures are in place to insure that your personal information is retained only as long as necessary for the purposes for which it was gathered;
      * you have reasonable access to any personal information you provide; and
      * there is a procedure for correcting or modifying your personal information, if appropriate.
  * ### Accountability

The Company is responsible for your personal Information under its control. The Company has appointed an officer who is accountable for the Company's compliance with these privacy principles. Chad Schron has been designated the Company's privacy officer in connection with these privacy principles. Chad Schron can be reached by telephone at (866) 706-6601, by e-mail at [info@toolingu.com](mailto:info@toolingu.com) or by regular mail to Tooling University, 3615 Superior Avenue East, Building 44, 6th Floor, Cleveland, Ohio 44114. Questions, requests for copies of policies or practices, comments or challenges concerning compliance should be directed to the privacy officer.

Unfortunately, neither Tooling University's computer systems, data storage systems, nor data transmission over the Internet, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of your personal information.

  * ### Children

We do not use the Website to knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 13.

  * ### Cookie Disclosure Information

A "cookie" is a persistent, client-side, hypertext transfer protocol file. Cookies are pieces of information that a Website can transfer to a visitor's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies facilitate web surfing by saving visitor preferences and other information. The rise of cookies is a widespread industry standard and thus many major websites use cookies. Using a cookie allows record-keeping while you are visiting a Website and saves you the extra effort of entering certain information multiple times in one site.

Most browsers are initially configured to accept and process cookies. You can configure your browser to refuse cookies. Extensive information concerning cookies is available on the World Wide Web by searching for the word "cookies." If you have any questions concerning our use of cookies, please contact our privacy officer.

We reserve the right to use cookies and related technologies on our Website.

  * ### Use and Disclosure of Aggregated, Non-Personally Identifiable Data 

Some information about your IP address, web browser, and computer system is automatically transmitted to our web servers as an integral part of the operation of the Internet and we reserve the right to automatically collect and/or track such data as well as information on what pages of the Website visitors access; and the date and time of a user's visit. In addition, information regarding what pages of the Website you access may be combined with data regarding your school or company and used and disclosed in a non-personally identifiable manner.

Non-personally identifiable data we collect will be aggregated and used for:

    * monitoring and improving our internal operations; 
    * producing statistical and/or demographic data for use by advertisers, potential advertisers, and other business partners; 
    * customizing content and layout of our site; and
    * marketing and promotional purposes as permissible under applicable law. 

  * ### Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

There are times when you may fill out a form on the Website or we may ask you for personal information including, but not limited to name, address, phone number, and credit card information (the "Personal Information"). This information will be requested only when needed to complete a transaction for which such information is necessary. We will not collect sensitive information (e.g. political or religious beliefs, ethnic origin, sexual orientation, health or medical condition).

Personal Information we collect will be used for:

    * billing you appropriately for contracted transactions and services; 
    * performing the services you request and provide the goods you request; 
    * responding to your inquiries; 
    * providing general information that may be of interest to you;
    * editorial and feedback purposes;
    * monitoring and improving our internal operations; 
    * producing statistical and/or demographic data for use by advertisers, potential advertisers, and other business partners; 
    * customizing content and layout of our site; and
    * marketing and promotional purposes as permissible under applicable law.

We will protect Personal Information against unauthorized access in accordance with applicable law.

  * ### Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties

By visiting the Website and providing the Company with data, you acknowledge and agree that the Company may use the data collected as set forth herein, and to provide the information to other selected third parties which may be outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, such data may be stored on servers located in other jurisdictions and transferred between jurisdictions. By providing the Company with your data, you consent to the transfer of such data.

We will not disclose Personal Information if such disclosure is prohibited under applicable law, and we will comply with applicable law in connection with any disclosures that are permitted thereunder. Any third party we share, rent, sell or otherwise disclose data to will be prescreened by us as part of reasonable efforts to ascertain that they are reputable and that they will use the Personal Information only for the processing purposes we request or marketing purposes that we determine you might be interested in and in accordance with applicable law. In all events, we will comply with our privacy obligations, if any, under FERPA. We will use reasonable efforts to make sure that all such third parties are contractually prohibited from using or disclosing Personal Information for any purposes other than for that which they have been engaged and they are contractually required to maintain the security of the Personal Information provided by the Company, and to process such Personal Information only on our instructions, in compliance with this Privacy Statement, and in an appropriate confidential and secure manner.

In accordance with California law, California residents are entitled to request certain disclosures regarding certain Personal Information the Company may provide to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Such disclosures will be provided to you, if required by law, and upon written request directed to the Company at: [info@toolingu.com](mailto:info@toolingu.com) or by regular mail to Tooling University, 3615 Superior Avenue East, Building 44, 6th Floor, Cleveland, Ohio 44114.

  * ### Consent and Opting Out

Our server does not automatically record Personal Information. Such information can become known to the Company only when you voluntarily submit it. By submitting your Personal Information, you are consenting to the collection, export, transfer, transport, transmission, use, or disclosure of your Personal Information.

You may opt out of having your Personal Information shared with third parties by contacting us by e-mail or regular mail. Please note that in order to fulfill certain obligations, we may need to continue sending you notices or other important information concerning your account.

  * ### Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

You may request, via e-mail or regular mail, that we provide you with a summary of personal information we retain concerning you or that we modify or remove any personal information we retain concerning you. Students participating in training programs may request removal of certain personal information in accordance with the Student Privacy Statement. We reserve the right, for security reasons, to verify your identity before performing your requests.

  * ### Special Circumstances

Due to the existing legal, regulatory and security environment, the Company may be required, under certain circumstances, to disclose records about Website usage including Personal Information. We will attempt to limit such disclosure to instances where we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in response to a subpoena or other legal process; where it is reasonably required to do so in order to maintain, update or otherwise implement our data security measures, equipment, technical operations and the like; or where reasonably necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities to preserve and/or enforce our rights.

Additionally, we may sell or otherwise transfer such information to a successor of the Company in connection with an asset sale, merger, consolidation, divestiture, stock sale or other corporate transaction, or by way of assignment (whether by operation of law or otherwise) in connection with any such or similar transaction or in connection with a liquidation or the administration of a bankruptcy estate.

  * ### Modifications

This Privacy Statement, along with the additional Student Privacy Statement listed below, were issued on October 14, 2011 and are subject to future modification at the election of the Company. In the event of a material modification to the terms and conditions of these Privacy Statements, the Company will post a notice on this page advising you of any such changes.

In addition to the terms set forth on the ToolingU.com (the "Company") Privacy Statement which apply to all users of this website (the "Website"), students enrolled in Tooling University courses ("Students") are also subject to the following specific privacy practices. We urge you to read this Student Privacy Statement in its entirety so that you will understand all of the practices and procedures that relate to your online privacy.

  * ### Overview

This Privacy Statement addresses your privacy by:

    * **Informing you about:**
      * the type of personal information the Company collects about you through this Website; 
      * how that information is collected; 
      * the general purposes for which information is collected; 
      * what disclosures of information will be made; 
      * how, and to what extent, you can limit those disclosures; and 

    * **Assuring you that:**
      * reasonable precautions are taken to protect your Education Records, including any Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosures, alteration, or destruction; 
      * Company employees who have access to your Education Records are informed about our privacy procedures for protecting such information; 
      * reasonable policies and procedures are in place to insure that the Company gathers only the information it needs in order to perform the tasks listed below and that your Education Records are retained only as long as necessary for the purposes for which they were gathered; 
      * you have reasonable access to any Education Records you provide; and 
      * there is a procedure for correcting or modifying your Education Records, if appropriate.

  * ### Accountability

The Company is responsible for your Education Records under its control. The Company has appointed an officer who is accountable for the Company's compliance with these privacy principles. Chad Schron Howard has been designated the Company's privacy officer in connection with these privacy principles. Chad Schron can be reached by telephone at (866) 706-6600, by e-mail at [info@toolingu.com](mailto:info@toolingu.com) or by regular mail to Tooling University, 3615 Superior Avenue East, Building 44, 6th Floor, Cleveland, Ohio 44114. Questions, requests for copies of policies or practices, comments or challenges concerning compliance should be directed to the privacy officer.

Unfortunately, neither Tooling University's computer systems, data storage systems, nor data transmission over the Internet, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Education Records, and to utilize such methods as are required under applicable law, since no method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of your Education Records.

  * ### Children

Students must be over the age of 18. Additionally, we do not use the Website to knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 13.

  * ### Cookie Disclosure Information

A "cookie" is a persistent, client-side, hypertext transfer protocol file. Cookies are pieces of information that a website can transfer to a visitor's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies facilitate web surfing by saving visitor preferences and other information. The rise of cookies is a widespread industry standard and thus many major websites use cookies. Using a cookie allows record-keeping while you are visiting a website and saves you the extra effort of entering certain information multiple times in one site.

Most browsers are initially configured to accept and process cookies. You can configure your browser to refuse cookies. Extensive information concerning cookies is available on the World Wide Web by searching for the word "cookies." If you have any questions concerning our use of cookies, please contact our privacy officer.

We reserve the right to use cookies and related technologies on our Website.

  * ### Internal Use of Education Records

PII as provided on the Create a Student Account page may be combined with other Education Records and used internally by the Company. We will not collect sensitive information (e.g., political or religious beliefs, ethnic origin, sexual orientation, health or medical condition) from Students.

Education Records we collect may be used by the Company for:

    * monitoring Student's participation and performance in training programs and identifying skill gaps; 
    * responding to Student inquiries; 
    * providing general information that may be of interest to Students;
    * editorial and feedback purposes;
    * monitoring and improving our internal operations; 
    * customizing content and layout of our site; and
    * marketing and promotional purposes as permissible under applicable law.

We will protect PII against unauthorized access in accordance with applicable law.

  * ### Use and Disclosure of Aggregated, Non-Personally Identifiable Data

Some information about your IP address, web browser, and computer system is automatically transmitted to our web servers as an integral part of the operation of the Internet and we reserve the right to automatically collect and/or track such information. In addition, information regarding what pages of the Website you access may be combined with data regarding your school or employer and used and disclosed in a non-personally identifiable manner.

Non-personally identifiable data we collect will be aggregated and used for:

    * monitoring and improving our internal operations; 
    * producing statistical and/or demographic data for use by advertisers, potential advertisers, and other business partners;
    * customizing content and layout of our site; and
    * marketing and promotional purposes as permissible under applicable law

  * ### Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties

_For all Students:_ We will not disclose PII if such disclosure is prohibited under applicable law, and we will comply with applicable law in connection with any disclosures that are permitted thereunder.

We may provide Student Directory Information (but not other Educational Records) to marketing partners. In addition, we may share Educational Records with outside service providers. Any third party we share, rent, sell or otherwise disclose data to will be prescreened by us to as part of reasonable efforts to ascertain that they are reputable and that they will use the data only for the processing purposes we request or marketing purposes that we determine you might be interested in and in accordance with applicable law. We will use reasonable efforts to make sure that all such third parties are contractually prohibited from using or disclosing Education Records for any purposes other than for that which they have been engaged and are required to maintain the security of the Education Records provided by the Company, and to process such Education Records only on our instructions, in compliance with this Privacy Statement, and in an appropriate confidential and secure manner.

_For all Students accessing Tooling University through an employer's account_ : We may provide administrative reports containing Educational Records to employers providing Tooling University accounts to its employees.

_For all Students accessing Tooling University through a school account_ : We may provide administrative reports containing Educational Records to schools providing Tooling University accounts to its students.

_For Students attending schools receiving funding from the U.S. Department of Education_ (each, a "School"): We will comply with our privacy obligations, if any, under The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 ("FERPA"). See Section VIII, below.

  * ### FERPA Rights

[Applies only to Students attending eligible Schools]

As a provider of outsourced training services to Schools, the Company is committed to Student rights under FERPA in connection with Education Records.

As such, Company will work with each School to ensure that Students can:

    * Inspect and review Education Records in Company's possession and under Company's control;
    * Request the correction of Education Records in Company's possession and under Company's control which the Student believes are inaccurate or misleading;
    * Opt-out of disclosure by Company to third parties of Directory Information by notifying Company in writing; and
    * In cases where Education Records include PII (excluding Directory Information), opt-in prior to Company's disclosure of any such information to third parties.

Company will only use Education Records provided by a School for the limited purposes for which the disclosure by the School was made. We reserve the right, for security reasons, to verify your identity before performing your requests.

  * ### Opting Out 

You may opt out of having your Directory Information and/or other personally identifiable Education Records shared with third parties by contacting us by e-mail or regular mail. Please note that in order to fulfill certain obligations, we may need to continue providing certain Education Records to your School or employer and sending you notices or other important information concerning your account.

  * ### Special Circumstances

Due to the existing legal, regulatory and security environment, the Company may be required, under certain circumstances, to disclose records about Website usage and/or Education Records. We will attempt to limit such disclosure to instances where we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in response to a subpoena or other legal process; where it is reasonably required to do so in order to maintain, update or otherwise implement our data security measures, equipment, technical operations and the like; or where reasonably necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities to preserve and/or enforce our rights.

  * ### CONSENT

I understand and agree that Education Records (defined above) about me may be collected, transmitted, stored and used by Tooling University and shared with third parties as set forth above. I understand that the privacy of Education Records and other information collected from me by Tooling University is governed by this Tooling University Student Privacy Statement.

I have read, understand and agree to abide by the Tooling University Student Privacy Statement.
